<?xml version="1.0"?>
<root available-locales="en_US" default-locale="en_US">
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Banner" type="document_library" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Cover_Image" type="document_library" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[Archbishop-Cupich-Informal_sm.jpg]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Title" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[Families The Privileged Place Of Gods Revelation]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Intro" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[These summer months will I hope provide each of us...]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Author" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[Archbishop Cupich]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Content" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[These summer months will I hope provide each of us with some leisure time to read. I know that a lot of children have put together a list of books for summer reading and that many even approach their reading as a contest with their peers. Reading opens us up to  a conversation with others.  It frees us from the  tyranny of "what’s happening  now" which too  often we allow to invade  our lives. One "book" worth reading  is Pope Francis’ recent  apostolic exhortation  "The Joy of Love" which he wrote  after the 2014 and 2015 synods on the  family. In the text itself Pope Francis  urges us to read the exhortation slowly  so that we can gradually absorb its  many insights. Over the next couple of  issues of the Chicago Catholic I will  offer some reflections on this important  work as a way of encouraging everyone  to take the time to read it and reflect  upon the pope’s beautiful thoughts  regarding Christian family life as he intended. From the outset the pope notes that  the church’s interest in family and married  life goes beyond addressing the  challenges we face in contemporary  life. Most assuredly as many bishops  pointed out during the synod marriage  and family life are faced by unique and  difficult challenges in our day. Yet Pope  Francis calls our attention to an important  truth found in Scripture the family  married life is the unique and privileged  place where God consistently reveals  himself and encounters humanity. In fact as the pope observes the entire  Bible is framed by  this truth "from its very  first page with the appearance  of Adam and  Eve’s family … to its  very last page where we  behold the wedding feast  of the Bride and the  Lamb" (Rv 212 9). Jesus himself witnesses  to this truth throughout  the Gospels having been  "born into a modest family  that soon had to flee to  a foreign land. He visits  the home of Peter whose  mother-in-law is ill (cf.  Mk 130-31) and shows  sympathy upon hearing of deaths in the  homes of Jairus and Lazarus (cf. Mk  522-24 35-43 Jn 111-44). He hears  the desperate wailing of the widow of  Nain for her dead son (cf. Lk 711-15)  and heeds the plea of the father of an  epileptic child in a small country town  (cf. Mk 917-27). He goes to the homes  of tax collectors like Matthew and Zacchaeus  (cf. Mt 99-13 Lk 191-10) and  speaks to sinners like the woman in the  house of Simon the Pharisee (cf. Lk  736-50). Jesus knows the anxieties and tensions  experienced by families and he  weaves them into his parables children  who leave home to seek adventure (cf.  Lk 1511-32) or who prove troublesome  (Mt 2128-31) or fall prey to violence  (Mk 121-9). He is also sensitive  to the embarrassment caused by the  lack of wine at a wedding feast (Jn 21-  10) the failure of guests to come to a  banquet (Mt 221-10) and the anxiety  of a poor family over the loss of a coin  (Lk 158-10). This simple truth that God has chosen  families as the privileged place to reveal  himself and encounter us has enormous  implications both for families and  how the church relates to families and  married couples. It should first of all encourage families  and married couples to treasure the  full breadth of their experiences — the  joys the sorrows the worries and wonderful  surprises the blessings and sufferings  — all as opportunities to experience  God working in the world. This is  why the pope insists that for the church  "families are not a problem they are  first and foremost an opportunity." He is urging us to see that it is precisely  in the limited circumstances and  the limited relationships of our lives  where God calls and graces us. Believing  this may take some doing but we  only need to go back to some of the  texts cited above by the pope to appreciate  the full weight of that truth.  Someone once said that "behind every  family is a mess." How true that is but  the pope seems to add to that by saying  that in the midst of that mess God is revealing  his saving work and power and  that is why we should value our families  and marriages. Likewise this truth of the privileged  place of families for God’s self-revelation  should shape the church’s ministry  and teaching on marriage and family  life. Just as "the word of God is not a  series of abstract ideas but rather a  source of comfort and companionship  for every family that experiences difficulties  or suffering" so too the church  must value and learn from the experiences  of families and married couples  because God is working and revealing  himself in those relationships. All of this is in keeping with the urging  of Pope Francis that pastors need to  minister in a way that always aims at  accompanying people as a shepherd  does his flock. What does it mean to accompany the  flock? In speaking to the Leadership of  the Episcopal Conferences of Latin  America on July 28 2013 Pope Francis  said that a pastor "has to be among  his people in three ways in front of  them pointing the way among them  keeping them together and preventing  them from being scattered and behind  them ensuring that no one is left behind  but also and primarily so that the  flock itself can sniff out new paths." The point is clear. Whenever church  leaders fail to walk with families and  married couples whenever they fail to  act as a source of comfort and compassion  in their people’s daily triumphs  and tragedies heartaches and heroics  they are not only negligent in their duty  but they also risk missing something of  God’s revelation and activity in the  world. Similarly by not treasuring and  valuing the experiences of families and  married couples the church is denied  the benefit of their acquired ability to   "sniff out new paths." This coming weekend we will hear a  similar message from St. Paul’s Second  Letter to Timothy "The word of the  Lord cannot be chained" not by our  faults nor by our strengths. There are many more nuggets of truth  in this exhortation some of which I  will write about over the coming  weeks. In the meantime I encourage  you to read this wonder work for yourself  at <a href="http  w2.vatican.va content francesco en apost_exhortations documents papa-francesco_esortazione-ap_20160319_amoris-laetitia.html" target="_blank">w2.vatican.va content francesco en apost_exhortations documents papa-francesco_esortazione-ap_20160319_amoris-laetitia.html.To read the other entries in this series of reflections <a href="http  www.chicagocatholic.com joyoflove">click here. ]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
</root>
