<?xml version="1.0"?>
<root available-locales="en_US" default-locale="en_US">
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Banner" type="document_library" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Cover_Image" type="document_library" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[Archbishop-Cupich-Informal_sm.jpg]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Title" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[Us Bishops To Immigrants We Stand With You]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Intro" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[Rev. Pawel Furdzik O.C.D. to pastor of St. Camillu...]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Author" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[Archbishop Cupich]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Content" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[Rev. Pawel Furdzik O.C.D. to pastor of St. Camillus Parish South Lockwood Avenue effective Nov. 2.Rev. Simon Braganza to administrator of Queen of All Saints Basilica North Sauganash Avenue effective from Jan. 1-June 30 2017Rev. Richard Alejunas S.D.B. to associate pastor of St. John Bosco Parish North McVicker Avenue effective Oct. 24. Rev. Drazan Boras O.F.M. to associate pastor of Blessed Alojzije Stepinac Croatian Catholic Mission North Ridge Avenue effective Oct. 23. Rev. Konrad Ciechanowski O. Cist. to associate pastor of Our Lady Mother of the Church Polish Mission Willow Springs effective Nov. 15. Rev. Arturo Felix O.F.M. Conv. to associate pastor of St. Ita Parish West Catalpa Avenue effective Oct. 24. Rev. Selvaraj Lucas M.S.C. to associate pastor of St. Joseph Parish South Hermitage Avenue effective Nov. 30. Rev. Jose Guadalupe Matus Castillo O.F.M. Conv. to associate pastor of St. Ita Parish West Catalpa Avenue effective Nov. 30. Rev. Jacek Palica O.C.D. to associate pastor of St. Camillus Parish South Lockwood Avenue effective Oct. 14. Rev. Robert Casey to be a member of the Diocesan Priests’ Placement Board while retaining his duties as pastor of St. Bede the Venerable Parish South Kostner Avenue effective Nov. 3. Rev. Roger Corrales-Diaz to be a member of the Diocesan Priests’ Placement Board while retaining his duties as pastor of St. Leonard Parish Berwyn effective Aug. 24. Msgr. Wayne Prist to be a member of the Diocesan Priests’ Placement Board effective Oct. 11.Rev. Pedro Campos from pastor of St. Kevin Parish South Torrence Avenue to sabbatical effective Dec. 1 2016 to June 1 2017. Msgr. John Pollard from pastor of Queen of All Saints Basilica North Sauganash Avenue to sabbatical effective Jan. 1 to June 30 2017. Rev. Andrew Smith from pastor of Holy Angels Parish East Oakwood Boulevard to sabbatical effective Jan. 2 to June 7 2017.When the Catholic bishops of the United States met in Baltimore this past November there was widespread support for developing a plan of action for a robust response to the increased risk faced by migrants and refugees in our country. In addition to offering needed spiritual and pastoral support the bishops spoke of the need to be prophetic in their advocacy on behalf of immigrants and also to build avenues for constructive engagement with policymakers.It was also clear that given the changing political landscape there was a need for the bishops to establish a working group on this issue so that our response would be timely and targeted in supporting those who are at risk.As a result Cardinal Daniel DiNardo president of the U.S. Conference of Catholic Bishops appointed a special working group charged with developing support for immigrants and refugees on three levels spiritual pastoral and policy advocacy.With the Dec. 12 feast of Our Lady of Guadalupe the working group is calling for a day of prayer and has developed resources that can be found on the <a href="http  www.usccb.org about migration-and-refugee-services national-migration-week ">USCCB website.The working group will also look at what is already being done pastorally in dioceses throughout the country and will share those best practices with the bishops. Particular attention will be given to addressing the economic struggles alienation fear and exclusion many feel along with the resistance to the church’s message regarding migrants and refugees. Emphasis will be given to ways we can build bridges between various segments of society.The working group will also spearhead advocacy building on existing efforts of the USCCB to engage constructively the incoming administration and Congress. The work of advocacy will involve developing resources for public distribution that outlines the USCCB position on migration and refugee issues (including but not limited to "sanctuary cities" deferred action refugee vetting).Cardinal DiNardo has invited Archbishop Jose Gomez of Los Angeles to chair the working group. Archbishop Gomez will be assisted by the chairmen of the USCCB committees and subcommittees whose jurisdictions encompass most directly the situation of immigrants and refugees Bishop Joe S. Vásquez chairman of the Committee on Migration Bishop Nelson J. Pérez chairman of the Subcommittee on Hispanic Affairs Bishop Frank J. Dewane chairman of the Committee on Domestic Social Development Bishop Joseph J. Tyson chairman of the Subcommittee on Pastoral Care of Migrants Refugees and Travelers and Bishop Oscar Cantú Chairman of the Committee on International Justice and Peace.Archbishop Gomez intends to convene the working group on a weekly basis and collaborate with other USCCB committees such as Doctrine Communications Ecumenical and Interreligious Affairs and Divine Worship.I personally welcome this strong initiative by the USCCB as it will send a message to those who live in fear that the Catholic bishops of the United States stand with them pray with them offer pastoral support and speak prophetically in defense of their human dignity.We in Chicago will continue to walk with all who given our broken immigration system live in the shadows. We will advocate for them as well as for refugees seeking a better life for their families. In time we will announce ways in which the archdiocese will coordinate with the USCCB but given this new development I thought it was important to inform our community of these efforts as we celebrate the Feast of Our Lady of Guadalupe. In launching this important effort the U.S. Catholic bishops are saying loudly and clearly to all immigrants and refugees "We stand with you!"]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
</root>
