<?xml version="1.0"?>
<root available-locales="en_US" default-locale="en_US">
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Banner" type="document_library" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Cover_Image" type="document_library" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[Archbishop-Cupich-Informal_sm.jpg]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Title" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[The Joy Of Love Dimensions Of Discernment For Disciples]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Intro" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[Rev. Hector Návalo C.M.F. to pastor of Our Lady of...]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Author" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[Archbishop Cupich]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Content" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[Rev. Hector Návalo C.M.F. to pastor of Our Lady of Guadalupe Parish East 91st Street effective immediately. Rev. Francis Xavier Rayappan S.V.D. to associate pastor of St. Joseph the Worker Parish Wheeling effective immediately. Rev. Sergio Enrique Rivas Tamayo O.S.B. to associate pastor of St. Agnes of Bohemia Parish South Central Park Avenue effective immediately. Rev. Homero Sanchez Gomez O.S.A. to associate pastor of St. Rita of Cascia Parish South Fairfield Avenue effective immediately. Rev. Brian Simpson to administrator of Queen of the Rosary Parish Elk Grove Village effective immediately. Rev. Marek Duran to director of the Abramowicz Seminary Program at the University of St. Mary of the Lake while retaining duties on the faculty of the University of St. Mary of the Lake effective July 1 2016. Rev. Collins Nyache from associate pastor of St. Ailbe Parish South Harper Avenue to full-time chaplain at University of Chicago Medical Center while retaining residence at St. Ailbe Parish effective July 1 2016. Rev. Daniel Cassidy from resident of St. Ita Parish West Catalpa Avenue to resident of Sacred Heart Parish Winnetka effective July 1 2016. Rev. Andrew Luczak from pastor of St. Isaac Jogues Parish Niles to retire after 46 years of service to the church.This is the fourth in a series of articles  on Pope Francis’ apostolic exhortation  "The Joy of Love."  To read the other entries in this series of reflections <a href="http  www.chicagocatholic.com joyoflove">click here.  "The Joy of Love"  Pope Francis’ response  to the 2014  and 2015 synods of bishops  marks a fresh and  even revolutionary approach  to the church’s  teaching on marriage and  family life. As I noted  earlier this approach is  anchored in the Holy Father’s  insight that as we  see throughout Scripture  God has chosen families  as the privileged place to  reveal himself and his  saving action in the  world. Pope Francis hopes to inspire families  and married couples to value more  fully their experiences as graced experiences  — as moments that help us all  discern God’s call. Likewise Francis  also uses this insight to urge pastors to  view the families they serve not as  problems to be solved but as opportunities  to better know God’s will. Marriage is best understood as "a dynamic  path to personal development"  the pope writes. As such pastors  should "make room for the consciences  of the faithful who very often  respond as best they can to the Gospel  amid their limitations and are capable  of carrying out their own discernment  in complex situations." The Holy Father  adds that pastors "have been  called to form consciences not to replace  them." Conscience according  to the Second Vatican  Council’s Pastoral Constitution  on the Church in  the Modern World is the  place where God’s "voice  echoes in (our) depths"  (n. 16). What then is involved  in forming our  consciences in order to  help us hear God’s voice  within us? Of course I can’t be exhaustive  in this space but  consider four decisions  all of us must make in the  process of forming our  consciences. First forming a faithful conscience  means learning to recognize the integrity  or wholeness of our lives. Our  lives do not amount to a series of unrelated  and unconnected episodes.  Rather our lives form a single and integral  sacred journey. It isn’t always easy to see things this  way. Life seems to move faster than  ever to be busier more scheduled.  This tempts us to view our lives as  made up of discrete parts. Many people  no longer live near their families or  those from their childhood years we  are more mobile than ever. This makes  it all too easy to lose a sense of connection  to the communities that formed  us. Those crucial childhood experiences  can seem lost to memory rather  than present to us in every moment because  they form the foundation on  which we build our lives. This is the age we live in. It is a secular  age known for its hyper-individualism  and emphasis on fulfillment in  the moment. This undermines our  sense of our lives as coherent sacred  and unique stories in which God plays  an indispensable role. So the first thing one must ask in the  process of discernment is How do I  think about my life? Do I approach it  only in terms of what is happening in  this moment or that or do I view it as a  dynamic journey with God and to God  as Scripture teaches? The biblical narratives of people  such as Abraham Sarah David and  Mary reveal their own unique journeys  with God. In each of their lives there  comes a moment in which they are  called to live the examined life. That is  the second decision we must make as  we practice discernment Will I take  responsibility for my life by working  to hear God’s call? You have heard the term "examination  of conscience." Unfortunately it  has too often been portrayed as making  a check list of our failures. But this is  too simplistic. If we look at the holy  men and women in Scripture we discover  a much richer approach to discerning  the will of God. It is one  marked by an openness to how God is  calling each of us in our particular circumstances  not only to correct our  sinfulness — which we must do — but  also to strike out on new paths with a  sense of wonder about our lives. So an authentic discernment must involve  questions such as "How and  when have I experienced God’s grace  and call in moments of loss accomplishment  sinfulness and reconciliation?  What have I learned about myself?  What good habits and virtues  have I acquired in those experiences?  What weaknesses have I struggled to  overcome on my own because I have  not allowed God’s grace to heal them? But as members of a vast and ancient  community of faith we know that we  are not alone in this. So a third decision  involves having the humility to  accept that we all need help in order to  discern God’s will. Without that help  we can all too easily allow ourselves to  believe that we have all the answers.  We can find assistance in the wisdom  that has been handed down to us over  the ages crystallized in the Word of  God proclaimed by the church and  visible in the examples of our brothers  and sisters in faith. We shouldn’t view this wisdom as a  list of do’s and don’t’s to be followed  unreflectively. Rather we should approach  it as a conversation with our forebears in faith. Our ancestors serve as a "cloud of witnesses"  the communion of saints whose lives were purified  by a Gospel that fulfills the law and the prophets.  These elders challenge us to live an authentic discipleship  of Jesus. Although it is true as Pope Francis notes in quoting St.  Thomas Aquinas that general rules cannot provide absolutely  for all particular situations they "can never be  disregarded or neglected." The task for us is to enter into a  conversation with this wisdom of the Christian tradition as  we discern the will of God in the particular circumstances  of our lives. The fourth decision in forming a faithful conscience has  to do with making God’s mercy the basis of our discipleship  in Jesus and our relationship with others. Mercy cannot  be just an abstract theory or something we aspire to  but something we come to know. It must be evident in the  way we live our lives. God offers his mercy in every moment. It grounds everything  we do. It defines our relationship with God and with  others. Last week Pope Francis spoke about this in a video  message for the Celebration of the Jubilee Year of Mercy  in the Americas which took place in Bogota Columbia.  St. Paul the pope observes "does not say ‘The Lord  spoke and told me’ or ‘The Lord showed me or taught me.’  He says ‘He treated me with mercy.’ For Paul his relationship  with Jesus was sealed by the way he treated him.  Far from being an idea a desire a theory — much less an  ideology — mercy is a concrete way of ‘touching’ weakness  of bonding with others of drawing closer to others." The test for discerning whether our consciences are  being formed faithfully is whether our experience of God’s  mercy defines our relationship with God and with others.  Are we willing to treat people with mercy as God treats us  with mercy? Are we willing to meet people where they are  and to love them unconditionally as God loves us? As Pope Francis expresses it this is about "a way of acting  that makes us give the best of ourselves so that others  can feel ‘treated’ in such a way that they feel that in their  lives the last word has not yet been spoken. Treated in  such a way that those who feel crushed by the burden of  their sins can feel relieved at being given another chance."  This imperative of mercy flows from our knowledge that  "mercy is the concrete act by which God seeks to relate to  his children." In the end forming a good conscience cannot be reduced  to simplistic questions of following a law doing what others  expect or feeling good about myself. Neither can the  idea of conscience be reduced to listening to the angel on  my right shoulder rather than the devil on the left. It is  deeper than that. Conscience involves the orientation of  our very being. Do we turn toward God? Do we do so in a  way that respects the whole of creation? At the heart of forming one’s conscience is one’s experience  of God whose name the Holy Father reminds us is  Mercy.To read the other entries in this series of reflections <a href="http  www.chicagocatholic.com joyoflove">click here. ]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
</root>
