<?xml version="1.0"?>
<root available-locales="en_US" default-locale="en_US">
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Banner" type="document_library" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Cover_Image" type="document_library" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[Archbishop-Cupich-Informal_sm.jpg]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Title" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[The Joy Of Love And The Need For An Authentic Church Discipline]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Intro" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[In my previous article on Pope Francis’ apostolic ...]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Author" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[Archbishop Cupich]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Content" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[In my previous article on Pope Francis’ apostolic  exhortation "The Joy of Love (CNW Aug. 7) I  referred readers to <a href="http  www.chicagocatholic.com RBonAL" target="_blank">Professor Rocco Buttiglione’s  comments on the document published last month in  the Vatican newspaper L’Osservatore Romano.  Known for his expertise on the writings  of St. John Paul II this esteemed  Italian scholar noted that some of the  "learned class" have expressed concern  about the pope’s appeal for a  pastoral care of people that is marked  more by mercy than rigorous enforcement  of rules. I too have heard these concerns.  Some have even argued that such an  approach will lead to a breakdown in  church discipline and confuse people  into thinking that when it comes to  one’s faith life anything goes. Of course any fair-minded person  reading the entire exhortation would  conclude that this concern has no  basis. Pope Francis wants discipline  but he wants the right kind of discipline. He is calling  for a discipline that aims at forming disciples  and not just enforcing rules. It is a discipline that respects how a person matures  in freedom. And it is a discipline that is based  on the Catholic tradition not a legalism that simply  considers "whether or not an individual’s actions  correspond to a general law or rule because that is  not enough to discern and ensure full fidelity to God  in the concrete life of a human being" as the Holy  Father observes. This is why a recovery of a discipline  more faithful to our tradition is especially urgent  as we offer pastoral care today. Let’s look at this kind of discipline more closely  from the perspective of how it aims at forming disciples  and is thereby more faithful to the Christian  tradition. For Francis what is most important in human formation  is a person’s growth through a life-long journey  that allows people to act intelligently and have  the internal freedom to exercise prudence that is to  say to act like adults. The goal of formation is not  simply to teach rules and carry out a  system of enforcement but to cultivate  freedom through ideas incentives examples  models and dialogue so that  people are led to do good on their own. The Holy Father’s counsel to parents  as they raise their children (chapter 7  see sidebar) is helpful in this regard.  We adults he writes should be concerned  not only with "where our children  are physically or where they are  at any given time but rather where  they are existentially where they stand  in terms of their convictions goals desires  and dreams." The goal in this formation  is to understand where our children  really are in their journeys. Or as  the pope puts it to ask "Where is their  soul?"In Chapter 7 of "The Joy of Love" Pope Francis offers advice to parents for raising children advice that applies to all of us Doing what is right means more than "judging what  seems best" or knowing clearly what needs to be  done as important as this is. Often we prove inconsistent  in our own con victions however firm they may  be even when our conscience dictates a clear moral  decision other factors sometimes prove more attractive  and powerful.We have to arrive at the point where the good that  the intellect grasps can take root in us as a profound  affective inclination as a thirst for the good that outweighs  other attrac tions and helps us to realize that  what we consid er objectively good is also good "for  us" here and now. A good ethical education includes  show ing a person that it is in his own interest to do  what is right.Today it is less and less effective to demand something  that calls for effort and sacrifice without clearly  pointing to the benefits which it can bring. Good  habits need to be developed. Even childhood habits  can help to translate important interiorized values into  sound and steady ways of acting. A person may be  sociable and open to others but if over a long period  of time he has not been trained by his elders to say  "Please" "Thank you" and "Sorry" his good interior  dis position will not easily come to the fore. <p style="margin-bottom0">The strengthening of the will and the repetition of  specific actions are the building blocks of moral conduct  without the conscious free and valued repetition  of certain patterns of good behav ior moral education  does not take place. Mere desire or an attraction  to a certain value is not enough to instill a virtue. Our concern for their maturation must be about  more than their physical and material well-being. It  must focus on their development of prudence good  judgment common sense the freedom to rethink  their own ideas to understand that their lives and  the life of the community are in their hands. Of course what the pope writes about raising  children applies to all of us as we mature throughout  our lives. It also has much to recommend to pastors  who must reshape their pastoral ministry as  they help people meet complex challenges. Pope Francis’ starting point is that there has to be  a "gradualness of pastoral care" one that starts with  a discernment of one’s situation through respectful  dialogue with the aim of helping a person to move  forward into a new freedom. Here the Holy Father  relies on St. John Paul II who "proposed the so-called ‘law of gradualness’ in the knowledge that the  human being ‘knows loves and accomplishes moral  good by different stages of growth.’" We have to be realistic as St. John Paul II noted  about the fact that everyone "advances gradually with  the progressive integration of the gifts of God and the  demands of God’s definitive and absolute love in his or  her entire personal and social life." This is the discipline  that all Christians must commit to as they reflect on  their lives. But there has to be a corresponding discipline for  those who offer pastoral care. They too must commit to  a disciplined approach of ministry marked by patience  as they try to understand a person’s situation always  avoiding the temptation to impulsively prescribe a one-size-fits-all solution. Pope Francis is urging all pastoral  ministers to achieve a level of apostolic discipline in  their outreach to people cultivating the virtue of patience  while eschewing the vice of sloth by opting for  "easy recipes." The Holy Father also makes clear that this approach to  discipline is in keeping with an approach that has deep  roots in our tradition. From its earliest days the church  imposed punishment to nudge the baptized to reflect on  their lives and repent. Yet punishment and even exclusion  were used as a last resort and for a limited period of  time. The goal was to help the penitent live an authentic life  a life in which all are accountable to the community. As  many have noted there is ample evidence in the New  Testament that the church exercised a discipline when it  came to participating in the Eucharist. But as the pope  notes it was always a therapeutic discipline one that always  provided a path forward for sinners — because the  church is for all of us and we are all sinners. Likewise the church developed a set of criteria to determine  a person’s responsibility for certain actions that  violated moral laws. There are three conditions for determining  personal culpability in weighing whether someone  has committed a mortal sin 1) the act must be a  grave matter 2) there must be full knowledge of the evil  act committed with deliberate consent and 3) the sinner  must have freely acted. As Pope Francis reminds us the Catechism of the  Catholic Church offers a good summary of those "circumstances  which mitigate moral responsibil ity and  mentions at length ‘affective immaturity force of acquired  habit conditions of anxiety or other psychological  or social factors that less en or even extenuate moral  culpability.’" This means that an automatic application of  a general rule to a particular case is not supported by the  tradition of the church. The Holy Father makes this point when he writes "I  earnestly ask that we always recall a teaching of St.  Thomas Aquinas and learn to incorporate it in our pastoral  discernment ‘Although there is necessity in the  general princi ples the more we descend to matters of detail  the more frequently we encounter defects. … In  mat ters of action truth or practical rectitude is not the  same for all as to matters of detail but only as to the  general principles and where there is the same rectitude  in matters of detail it is not equally known to all. … The  principle will be found to fail according as we descend  further into detail.’ It is true that general rules set forth a  good which can never be disregarded or neglected but in  their formulation they cannot provide absolutely for all  particular situations." The pope is calling for a pastoral approach that is  marked by disciplined discernment which makes demands  of each believer but also of those involved in pastoral  care. He is urging all of us to be adults to take responsibility  for maturing into authentic human beings. But he is also telling all of us pastors to walk patiently  with those we serve. When we do this when we respect  how men and women mature in freedom we are more  faithful to our tradition. The great promise in doing this  a promise that motivates and inspires Pope Francis is to  position the church to take up with freshness the mission  of Christ to set the world ablaze.To read the other entries in this series of reflections <a href="http  www.chicagocatholic.com joyoflove">click here. ]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
</root>
