<?xml version="1.0"?>
<root available-locales="en_US" default-locale="en_US">
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Banner" type="document_library" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Cover_Image" type="document_library" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Title" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[Responsibility And The Rite Of Baptism]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Intro" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[Full disclosure For as long as I have  been aware ...]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Author" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[Kerry Alys Robinson]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Content" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[Full disclosure For as long as I have  been aware I have passionately loved  the church and held its potential in the  highest esteem. Its explicitly religious  mission has formed the person I am today.  That it is the largest humanitarian  network in the world renders me forever  committed to its health and vitality. This is neither blind love nor infatuation  but love borne of time and gratitude  and possibility. The more I am engaged  in the life of the church the more  I become aware of its history its mission  its ministries and its capacity. The  church has ennobled me and at times  broken my heart. Seventy-two years ago my great  grandparents John and Helena Raskob  established a private family foundation  with two intentions. They wanted  all of the foundation’s resources to be  used exclusively to support the Catholic  Church throughout the world and they  wanted their children and descendants  to be stewards of the foundation’s resources.  All participation is voluntary  non-remunerative and understood to be  a serious commitment of time focus and  engagement in the life of the church. Today there are nearly 100 members  all descendants of John and Helena actively  engaged in the work of the Raskob  Foundation. It has been an uncommon  privilege to serve the church in this way  with the unanticipated beneficial consequence  of evangelization for our family. Our faith lives are stronger because we  have had the opportunity to meet learn  from and support some of the most inspiring  generous effective people the  global church has to offer. We have seen  the very best of the church through the  lens of their ministries. We have also seen tremendous challenges  facing the church and have been  brought up to believe that we have an  obligation to help solve those challenges  regardless of how dicult or seemingly  insurmountable they may be. A beloved professor spiritual director  and Sister of Mercy once advised "Remember  what it is you most love about  the church and membership in it. Name  what you love. Claim what you love. It  will provide ballast to allow you to navigate  with fidelity and focus when you are  disappointed and discouraged." I have taken this advice to heart and  highly recommend the discipline. My  list is long and wide. I love our church’s  rich intellectual tradition social justice  teaching the community of saints  sacramental life and imagination mercy  the Eucharist the primacy of conscience  prayer and transcendence forgiveness  the preferential option for the  poor the injunction to be Christ-like.  I love that where there is human suffering  the church is at the vanguard of  providing relief promoting justice and  advocating for peace. Good catechesis allows for the appropriation  and cultivation of a mature  adult faith to live out one’s faith in the  world the better to transform it through  service and mercy generosity and grace.  This responsibility also extends to the  church itself. Lay participation leadership  generosity and active engagement  in the life of the church are vital for its  own transformation and mission efficacy.  Exercising baptismal responsibility  means actively contributing one’s gifts  and expertise to strengthen the church. Taking responsibility for the church  calling it to greater levels of holiness accountability  transparency and trust is a  responsibility of baptism. This understanding  inspired Geoff Boisi to create  the Leadership Roundtable a network  of Catholic leaders whose sole mission is  to help solve temporal challenges facing  the church by harnessing intellectual  problem-solving capability entrepreneurial  acumen contemporary best  practices and a profound commitment  to excellence and ethics. Baptism is our gift. Exercising responsibility  to ensure the church is welcoming  accountable effective and the very  best it can be is our right and our duty. Robinson is the founding executive  director and global ambassador of the  Leadership Roundtable. ]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
</root>
