<?xml version="1.0"?>
<root available-locales="en_US" default-locale="en_US">
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Banner" type="document_library" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Cover_Image" type="document_library" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[Archbishop-Cupich-Informal_sm.jpg]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Title" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[Christ Came Back From The Dead For Us]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Intro" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[ From the earliest days of the church to this very...]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Author" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[Archbishop Cupich]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Content" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[ From the earliest days of the church to this very night of our vigil service the Christian community has kept fresh a central truth we celebrate on Easter Just as Christ came into the world to save us came into the world for us so too he rose from the dead to save us. He came back from the dead for us. The resurrection story is incomplete if it is told just as a personal victory for Jesus of Nazareth for the innocent one nailed to a cross. It is also about our rising to new life. Nowhere is that more evident than in the striking absence of the Risen Christ in the Gospel for the Easter liturgies. Notice how there is no account of his appearances no report by witnesses of his actual departure from the tomb. Rather the emphasis throughout our liturgy in word and symbolic action is placed on what happens to the disciples whether those recounted in the Gospel of Luke or those who will join our Christian community in the rites of Christian initiation. Christ is indeed risen but we witness his resurrection in the rising that takes place in each of us. Just as the Easter fire lit at the beginning of the Easter Vigil allows us to move through the darkness of night so too do the readings and the rites provide insight into how Christ is raising us to new life and how he calls us to believe something new about our lives. We are told in the Gospel that the women who accompanied Jesus from Galilee and who are mourning his death rise early on the first day of the week. The resurrection begins a new day and a new week just as creation did. From the outset there is a signal that this day is different from any other. God is doing something altogether new just as he did at creation and we are invited to believe that. There is a certain irony about this new day on which new life begins for it starts off with a visit to a tomb a visit to the dead. What a strange way to begin a new life. But there is truth in this irony for the new life offered to these women begins when they confront all their fears the fears that death brings the fear that our past deeds have totally estranged us from God the fear that we are stuck because our sins have paralyzed us with shame the fears that make us fretful about the future. The women are invited to confront the fears of death in all its forms and leave them behind. It is for this reason that Christian baptisteries over the centuries have been shaped to resemble tombs. Baptism is a stepping into death expressing so vividly that the new life offered to us involves facing our mortality our weaknesses the shame of the past and our anxieties of what lies ahead. So this new day of Easter begins for us with a visit to the tomb not only for those who will step into the death of baptismal waters but for all of us. Each of us is invited to leave behind at the tomb the death of shame for our past sins and the death of anxiety that paralyzes our future. It is an invitation to believe that this is a new day and that we can walk away from the tomb free to announce Christ is risen because we experience him rising in us giving us new life. Is that not what the women do next? They return to the 11 and announce that Jesus is risen. While the credibility of what they say is challenged the apostles recognize that something new has happened to them. This is why Peter who represents the 11 and all of us springs up and races to the tomb. He saw what happened to these women and he wanted that. That is why he returns to the tomb and enters it leaving behind death the death of his shame for denying Jesus the death of fearing that Jesus will reject him because he abandoned him the death that comes from worrying about the future as he is overcome by his fears and shame. Peter leaves all of that behind and returns home amazed. We would not be here tonight if we did not want the same thing that happened to these women to Peter and to all the disciples hence. In a moment we will once again have in our hand the Easter fire as we prepare to renew our baptismal promises. It will remind us of the need to keep aflame the desire to have what these early disciples had and to leave behind at the tomb death in all its forms — our sinfulness our shame our anxieties. If we do that these early followers of Jesus — Mary Magdalene Joanna Mary the mother of James Peter and the other 11 — speak across the ages to remind us that if we leave death at the tomb we too will return home amazed.Archbishop Cupich approved the following appointments  Rev. Esequiel Sanchez from pastor of St. Bede the Venerable Parish South Kostner Avenue to rector of the Shrine of Our Lady of Guadalupe Des Plaines effective March 5.Rev. Robert Krueger to administrator of St.   Bede the Venerable Parish South Kostner Avenue effective immediately.  Rev. Brian Simpson to administrator of St. Colette Parish   Rolling Meadows effective March 1-May 31.  Rev. Benjamin Arevalos Lupercio from associate   pastor of Most Blessed Trinity Parish Waukegan to sabbatical   effective July 15 2016 to Jan. 15 2017.  Rev. Msgr. Richard Hynes from director of the Department   of Parish Life and Formation Cardinal Meyer Center to sabbatical   effective May 1-Aug. 31.  Rev. Michael Meany from pastor of St. John Brebeuf Parish   Niles to sabbatical effective June 6-Dec. 6.   Rev. George Omwando from pastor of St. Catherine of   Siena-St. Lucy Parish Oak Park to sabbatical effective July 1-   Dec. 31.  Rev. Stanley Rataj from pastor of Our Lady of the Snows   Parish South Leamington Avenue to sabbatical effective June   6-July 29.]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
</root>
