<?xml version="1.0"?>
<root available-locales="en_US" default-locale="en_US">
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Banner" type="document_library" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Cover_Image" type="document_library" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[Archbishop-Cupich-Informal_sm.jpg]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Title" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[A Church That Teaches And Learns]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Intro" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[In my previous column I began a series  of reflect...]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Author" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[Archbishop Cupich]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Content" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[In my previous column I began a series  of reflections on Pope Francis’  apostolic exhortation "The Joy of  Love" which he issued after the two  synods on the family and married life.  As I noted the pope begins  by drawing attention  to how the Bible repeatedly  testifies to the fact that  God has chosen to reveal  himself through the experiences  of families. In  fact the Holy Father reminds  us the Bible is replete  with examples of  how the family is the privileged  place where salvation  history takes place  and is revealed. As a result  married couples and  families should find in the  text a fresh understanding  and a deeper appreciation  of their dignity and importance to the  work and plan of God in the world. Similarly this insight also has consequences  for those involved in the  church’s pastoral outreach namely to  respect the experiences of families and  married couples taking those experiences  as the starting point for ministry  to them. This means that pastors and  other ministers must not only teach but  also learn from married couples and  families who on a daily basis offer us a  lesson on the meaning of sacrificial  love as they care for children elderly  parents and ailing spouses. Pope Francis made this very point in  one of his addresses during last October’s  synod on the family. He told the  bishops that we need to be both a teaching  church and a learning or a discerning  church — an "ecclesia docens" and  an "ecclesia discens." Pastors must approach  their ministry with an openness  and willingness to develop a capacity to  learn so that they in turn can help families  discern God’s call and God’s grace  in their lives. In chapters 2 and 3 Francis unpacks  this insight by reminding  us that marriage is a vocation.  Marriage therefore  is best understood  "more as a dynamic path  to personal development  and fulfilment than as a  lifelong burden." To the  extent that the church’s  support of families and  married couples simply  stresses "doctrinal  bioethical and moral issues  without encouraging  openness to grace" it falls  short. In other words if  we are a teaching church  but not a learning church  then we are failing our families. The pope acknowledges that this  change in approach will be demanding  if we see ourselves only as teachers  who give pat answers to complex questions  "We … find it hard to make room  for the consciences of the faithful who  very often respond as best they can to  the Gospel amid their limitations and  are capable of carrying out their own  discernment in complex situations."  Then he adds quite pointedly "We  have been called to form consciences  not to replace them." Just as the pope recalls the church’s  longstanding tradition of the inviolability  of conscience he is just as emphatic  in emphasizing that God’s grace is active  in the concrete situations of families  and married couples. It is God’s  grace that makes real conversion possible.  The church’s ministry then should  aim at helping people recognize God’s  grace in their lives. When we pastors fail to help people  see those graced moments and situations  we end up proposing "a far too  abstract and almost artificial theological  ideal of marriage far removed from the  concrete situations and practical possibilities  of real families." We have to set  our sights higher and work with married  couples and families in a way that  inspires trust in God’s grace thus making  marriage "more desirable and attractive." At the same time married couples are  encouraged to see that by making a  commitment by saying "I do" they are  taking responsibility for one another.  Practically this means assuming "an  active and creative role in a lifelong  project." As such "neither spouse can  expect the other to be perfect. Each  must set aside all illusions and accept  the other as he or she actually is an unfinished  product needing to grow a  work in progress. … By saying ‘I do’  they embark on a journey that requires  them to overcome all obstacles standing  in the way of their reaching the goal." Couples take up this journey armed  with mercy and forgiveness two prominent  themes in the exhortation. Sin can  and does distort God’s gift of married  love. Only mercy and forgiveness the  true graces of the sacrament of matrimony  can restore it. The Holy Father’s trust in God’s  grace his respect for a person’s conscience  and his call to learn from the experiences  of the faithful have opened up  a fresh way for the church for married  couples and for those who minister to  them and their families. He is calling  couples to take responsibility for their  own growth and maturing. He is calling  those who minister to families to assist  them in discerning God’s grace working  in their lives fully respectful of their experiences  and their consciences. Of  course all of this involves a major shift  both for couples and pastoral leaders. Professor Rocco Buttiglione — a  scholar who earned the admiration of  Pope Benedict XVI and St. John Paul II  — recently wrote about the difficulty  some are having with understanding  and accepting what Pope Francis is proposing.  In the official Vatican newspaper  L’Osservatore Romano Buttiglione  argued that the Christian people  through their appreciation of the faith  or "sensus fidei" "immediately embraced  and followed" the pope as he  advocates this new approach. Yet "some of the learned class seem  to have trouble understanding him" he  continued. Their criticism focuses on a  section of the exhortation "where the  pope says that in certain conditions and  in certain circumstances some divorced  and remarried people may receive the  Eucharist." They seem not to understand  Buttiglione observes that this  possibility entails an honest and demanding  process of discernment. It is  hardly a carte blanche or "easy pass" to  do anything we please. During last fall’s Synod on the Family  I spoke to journalists about the inviolability  of conscience and the importance  of the formation of conscience. I  will expand on this theme — essential  as it is to understanding "The Joy of  Love" — in the next issue of the  Catholic New World with a focus on  Buttiglione’s commentary as it relates  to Pope Francis’ emphasis on respecting  the consciences of men and women. For now I encourage you to read  Buttiglione’s important article which  can be found at <a href="http  www.chicagocatholic.com rbonal">www.chicagocatholic.com rbonal.To read the other entries in this series of reflections <a href="http  www.chicagocatholic.com joyoflove">click here. ]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
</root>
