<?xml version="1.0"?>
<root available-locales="en_US" default-locale="en_US">
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Banner" type="document_library" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Cover_Image" type="document_library" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[Archbishop-Cupich-Informal_sm.jpg]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Title" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[Kids Cards]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Intro" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[ Take for instance the sixth-grader who counselled...]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Author" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[Archbishop Cupich]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Content" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[ Take for instance the sixth-grader who counselled me "Don’t believe what everybody says about you." That good advice cuts both ways reminding me not to get puffed up when I am complimented but also not to be discouraged when I am criticized. Of course like all of us I have my family to keep me humble. One relative after seeing all the news coverage about me observed "I don’t get it you’re just not that interesting!" At this point I think I will take that sixth-grader’s advice. Then I read a note from a girl in third grade "I know you have a lot of things to do that are new but I hope you have fun once in a while." That is a message I want to put on my refrigerator to remind me each day that the tasks facing me cannot become a drudgery. They have to be even with the stress they bring occasions of joy the kind of joy that comes in experiencing the support and partnership of others serving with me a common purpose. I hope if I meet up with her she will ask me if I am having fun yet. An eighth-grade boy told me that when he has problems he says the prayer of St. Ignatius and it helps him. Aside from the fact that this is fairly profound advice from a 13-year-old I have to admit I have benefitted for many years from saying this same prayer known as the Suscipe Take Lord and receive all my liberty  my memory my understanding and my  entire will. All I have and call my own  you have given all to me. To you Lord I  return it. Everything is yours do with it  what you will. Give me only your love  and your grace that is enough for me.  The most common promise made to me in all of these cards is that they are praying for me. A lot of people are telling me they are praying for me but I have to admit there is something special about hearing that promise from a child. There is just something so genuine about it. For many years now I have become increasingly convinced that adults too often overlook the spiritual life of children. We grown-ups seem to give little attention to how God is deeply active in and present to children. Yet in my experience children have a perception and sensitivity to the spiritual life that is quite profound. We give a lot of attention to the physical intellectual and emotional health of children which we well should in these formative years. But we should not overlook that there is an awareness in each of them of the things of God spiritual acuity of God’s presence in the world and in their lives. So when they tell me that they are praying for me I am greatly encouraged. They have I believe a front row seat in the audience with God which prayer gives each of us. Let me make one small suggestion by way of being encouraged and encouraging children in this season of the child. Ask a child a son or daughter a niece or nephew a grandchild or student to pray for you. Let him or her know you depend on them and their prayers. I do and I am refreshed by the deluge of prayers they are sending   my way.<p id="carchive_link" style="padding-top10px margin-top10px border-top1px solid #818181"><a href=" cnwonline archbishop_archive.aspx">ArchiveArchbishop Cupich approved the following clergy appointments Rev. Robert Cook   OFM Conv. to administrator of St.   Nicholas Parish Evanston effective immediately.  Rev. George Schopp to administrator of   Maternity BVM Parish North Avenue   while retaining his duties as pastor of Our   Lady of Grace Parish North Hamlin.  Rev. Msgr. Richard   Zborowski from St. Anthony Health System   Alton Illinois to associate pastor of   Resurrection Parish North Francisco effective   immediately.  Rev. Miguel Alvarez CS to dean   of Deanery IV-B while retaining his duties   as pastor of Our Lady of Mount Carmel   Parish Melrose Park effective immediately.  Rev. Nicholas Desmond to co-dean of   Deanery III-A while retaining his duties as   pastor of St. Aloysius Parish Chicago and   dean of Deanery III-B effective immediately.  Rev. Lawrence Dowling to co-dean of   Deanery III-A while retaining his duties as   pastor of St. Agatha Parish West Douglas   Boulevard and dean of Deanery III-D effective   immediately.   Rev. Kevin Birmingham from pastor   of Maternity BVM Parish North Avenue   and from dean of Deanery III-A to   administrative secretary to the archbishop   with residence at Holy Name Cathedral effective   immediately.]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
</root>
