<?xml version="1.0"?>
<root available-locales="en_US" default-locale="en_US">
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Banner" type="document_library" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Cover_Image" type="document_library" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[Archbishop-Cupich-Informal_sm.jpg]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Title" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[Some Anniversaries Marked But Not Celebrated]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Intro" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[ The first hand-held cellular phone call was made ...]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Author" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[Archbishop Cupich]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
  <dynamic-element name="Column_Content" type="text_box" index-type="keyword" index="0">
    <dynamic-content language-id="en_US"><![CDATA[ The first hand-held cellular phone call was made and the World Trade Center was officially opened in New York. And on Jan. 22 the U.S. Supreme Court handed down the Roe v. Wade decision which overturned all state and federal laws restricting abortions in defense of the child in the womb. Much time has passed and many events have occurred since that tragic day in the winter of 1973 but one fact should not go unnoticed Over 50 million American children have been denied the fundamental right to life over these 3 1 2 decades. The number of abortions is staggering. We as a society need to recognize the harm that has been done to these children their mothers and to our nation's soul. To mark the 41st anniversary of the Supreme Court's decision to legalize abortion in our country I will join in events here in Chicago and in Washington D.C. I urge Catholics to fast on Jan. 22 and I ask prayers in our parishes for an end to abortion and a change of heart for all those involved in taking the life of the unborn the weekend of Jan. 24-25. Our common prayer and sacrifice are precisely what the Lord encourages us to do in the face of the seemingly overwhelming forces that degrade our dignity as children of God. We can pray to God to move the hearts of all of our fellow citizens to value the dignity of human life. We should also work together to promote laws that protect human life starting with the unborn and that create a just society through a livable wage adequate health care for families and assistance to mothers. Anniversaries are normally happy occasions. Sadly this one is not but we cannot let it go by without marking the loss of so many millions of our children and the damage done to our nation's soul. We owe it to them and to our nation to pause and beg God for the grace of conversion so that 41 years hence we will have something to celebrate.<p id="carchive_link" style="padding-top10px margin-top10px border-top1px solid #818181"><a href=" cnwonline archbishop_archive.aspx">ArchiveVery Rev. Ronald Hicks   from dean of formation Mundelein Seminary   Mundelein to vicar general of the   Archdiocese of Chicago effective immediately.   Most Rev.   Francis Kane from vicar general of the   Archdiocese of Chicago to episcopal vicar   of Vicariate II effective immediately.   Rev. Grzegorz Gorczyca   from associate pastor of St. William   Parish North Sayre to administrator of St.   John the Evangelist Parish Streamwood   effective immediately.  Rev. Krzysztof A. Kulig from associate   pastor of St. Thomas Becket Parish Mount   Prospect to administrator of the same effective   immediately.   Rev. Ronald   Kalas from vicar of Vicariate II to covicar   for senior Priests while retaining his   duties as dean of Deanery II-E effective   Feb. 1.]]></dynamic-content>
  </dynamic-element>
</root>
